Office of the Dean, Tufts Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences Records UA171
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of the Dean, Tufts Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences Records
1962 -- 2015
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences
Office of the Dean of the Sackler School
Tufts Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences
UA171
35.3 Linear Feet 25 boxes
19 Digital Object(s)
1 Volumes
14.3 Megabytes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series: Student records; Grade reports; Catalogs and handbooks; 2017 accessions; and Unprocessed accessions.
Custodial History
Eight boxes were transferred from the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences. Due to an accident en route to the DCA, one box was delivered with papers and folders askew. No files were missing. See collection documentation for incidence description. Loose documents in that box were placed into their proper folders during processing. These folders are: Berg, Allison; Andrews, Helene; Andersen, Jessica.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences, 2009-2017.
Biographical / Historical
The Tufts Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences was first established as the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences in 1980, and it appointed its first dean, Dr. Louis Lasagna, in 1985. Prior to his career at the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences, Dr. Lasagna revised the Hippocratic Oath and contributed greatly to the methodology of controlled clinical trials and the understanding of the placebo effect. During his tenure at Tufts, the size of the faculty tripled and the number of students in the School grew from 40 to 250. He also oversaw the formation of the School's two divisions, the Basic Science Division and Clinical Research Division, in 1999. Dr. Lasagna stepped down from the position in 2001. He was succeeded by biochemistry professor Dr. David Stollar, who served as Interim Dean from 2002 to 2004. Dr. Naomi Rosenberg was then appointed as the Dean in 2004. She first joined the faculty at Tufts Medical School in 1977 and was one of the first faculty at the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences, where her research focused on the mechanisms of leukemia development. Dr. Rosenberg was the recipient of the National Institute of Health MERIT Award (1983) and the Tufts Zucker Award for Excellence in Research (1994). During her time as Dean, she focused on providing student access to federal training grants, ensuring students had adequate career preparation, and creating a diversity program. Dr. Rosenberg retired in 2017. In December 2019, the name of the School was changed from the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences to the Tufts Graduate of Biomedical Sciences due to role of the Sackler family and their company, Purdue Pharma, in the opioid epidemic.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes student records kept by the Office of the Dean for students admitted to and enrolled in the programs of Tufts Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences (formerly known as the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences), as well as grade sheets submitted to the Office of the Dean. This collection also includes annual reports, program catalogs and handbooks, meeting minutes and agendas, and a scrapbook.
Administration and Governance -- Planning, evaluation, policies & procedures; Curriculum and Instruction -- Scholarships, Fellowships, Awards
- Grade Reports, 1978 -- 2002; UA171.002; 2.4 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  Grade sheets submitted to the Office of the Dean, Sackler School. Grade sheets were used to record the final grades for all students in a course.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation.
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1978; UA171.002.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1980; UA171.002.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1980; UA171.002.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1981; UA171.002.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1981; UA171.002.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1982; UA171.002.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1982; UA171.002.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1983; UA171.002.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1983; UA171.002.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1985; UA171.002.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1984; UA171.002.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1985; UA171.002.008.00012 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1985; UA171.002.008.00013 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1986; UA171.002.008.00014 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1986; UA171.002.008.00015 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1987; UA171.002.008.00016 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall 1987, 1 of 2, UA171.002.008.00017 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall 1987, 2 of 2, UA171.002.008.00018 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring 1988, 1 of 2, UA171.002.008.00019 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring 1988, 2 of 2, UA171.002.008.00020 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1988; UA171.002.008.00021 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1989; UA171.002.008.00022 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1989; UA171.002.008.00023 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1990; UA171.002.008.00024 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1990; UA171.002.008.00025 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1991; UA171.002.008.00026 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1991; UA171.002.008.00027 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1992; UA171.002.008.00028 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall 1992, 1 of 2, UA171.002.008.00029 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall 1992, 2 of 2, UA171.002.008.00030 (Box 8)
  - Grade Change Forms, 1990 -- 1993; UA171.002.008.00031 (Box 8)
  - Change of Grade Forms, 1 of 2, 1990 -- 1993; UA171.002.008.00032 (Box 8)
  - Change of Grade Forms, 2 of 2, Withdrawal, 1999; UA171.002.008.00033 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1993; UA171.002.008.00034 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1993; UA171.002.008.00035 (Box 8)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1994; UA171.002.009.00001 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Summer, 1994; UA171.002.009.00002 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1994; UA171.002.009.00003 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1995; UA171.002.009.00004 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Summer, 1995; UA171.002.009.00005 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1995; UA171.002.009.00006 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1996; UA171.002.009.00007 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Summer, 1996; UA171.002.009.00008 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1996; UA171.002.009.00009 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1997; UA171.002.009.00010 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Summer, 1997; UA171.002.009.00011 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1997; UA171.002.009.00012 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1998; UA171.002.009.00013 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Summer, 1998; UA171.002.009.00014 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1998; UA171.002.009.00015 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 1999; UA171.002.009.00016 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Summer, 1999; UA171.002.009.00017 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 1999; UA171.002.009.00018 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 2000; UA171.002.009.00019 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Summer, 2000; UA171.002.009.00020 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 2000; UA171.002.009.00021 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 2001; UA171.002.009.00022 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Summer, 2001; UA171.002.009.00023 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Fall, 2001; UA171.002.009.00024 (Box 9)
  - Grade Reports Spring, 2002; UA171.002.009.00025 (Box 9)
- Catalogs and handbooks, 1999 -- 2015; UA171.001004; 19 Digital Object(s); 14.3 Megabytes
  The records in this series are in chronological order.
  This series is open for research.
  This series contains student handbooks and catalogs for the Tufts Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences beginning in the 1999-2000 academic year.
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 1999 -- 2000; UA171.001005; 1 Digital Object(s); 252 Kilobytes
    Open for research.
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Catalog, 2000 -- 2002; UA171.001006; 1 Digital Object(s); 6703 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Catalog, 2004 -- 2005; UA171.001007; 1 Digital Object(s); 840 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2004 -- 2005; UA171.001008; 1 Digital Object(s); 1163 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2005 -- 206; UA171.001009; 1 Digital Object(s); 539 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2006 -- 2007; UA171.001010; 1 Digital Object(s); 259 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2007 -- 2008; UA171.001011; 1 Digital Object(s); 252 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2008 -- 2009; UA171.001012; 1 Digital Object(s); 291 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Catalog, 2009 -- 2010; UA171.001013; 1 Digital Object(s); 223 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2009 -- 2010; UA171.001014; 1 Digital Object(s); 301 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2010 -- 2011; UA171.001015; 1 Digital Object(s); 485 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Catalog, 2011 -- 2012; UA171.001016; 1 Digital Object(s); 247 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2011 -- 2012; UA171.001017; 1 Digital Object(s); 546 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2012 -- 2013; UA171.001018; 1 Digital Object(s); 413 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Catalog, 2012 -- 2013; UA171.003.020; 512 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s)
    Sackler School course catalog 2012-2013
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Transferred by the Office of the Dean of the Sackler School, 2013, accession 2017.026.
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Catalog, 2013 -- 2014; UA171.001019; 1 Digital Object(s); 335 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2013 -- 2014; UA171.001020; 1 Digital Object(s); 457 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Catalog, 2014 -- 2015; UA171.001021; 1 Digital Object(s); 338 Kilobytes
  - Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences Student Handbook, 2014 October; UA171.001022; 1 Digital Object(s); 486 Kilobytes
- 2017 accessions, circa 1980 -- 2013; UA171.003; 2 Linear Feet
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains student files for graduates and withdrawals between 2010 and 2012; an MD-PhD handbook for the school year of 1981-1982; an MD-PhD Executive Council meeting agenda from 9/28/1994; the MD/PhD Executive Committee meeting minutes from 2/13/1991; a binder of MD-PhD rotation placements and grades for students between 1995 and 2002; and one large format scrapbook with articles and photographs from the 1980's.
  Records containing information related to student education, staff and faculty employment, and Board of Trustees records are closed for 75 years from the date of creation.
  Transferred by the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences, 2017, accession UA-2017-053 and 2017.026.
  - Student files, handbooks, meeting agendas and minutes, 1981 -- 2012; UA171.003.018; 1.2 Linear Feet 1 record carton (Box 18)
    75 years from date of creation.
    Transferred by the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences, 2017, accession UA-2017-053.
  - Scrapbook, circa 1980 -- 1989; UA171.003.019; .8 Linear Feet 1 scrapbook (Box 19)
- Pre-2017 accessions, 1962 -- 2015; UA171.004; 7.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains publications, student records, photographs, and historical material pertaining to the Sackler Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences. Publications include catalogs, handbooks, course listings, and reports by or about the school, including self-study, accreditation, and annual reports. Student records include grade reports, grade books, grade sheets, and accepted applications for the Building Diversity in Biomedical Sciences (BDBS) Program, a ten week mentored research experience for students interested in pursuing degrees at the Sackler Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences. Photographs include class photographs and building photographs. Historical materials include the founding documents of the Sackler Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences from 1980, reports from the New England Association of Schools and Colleges and Tufts University, and documents from the first two deans of the school, Sidney Leskowitz, MD (acting dean) and Louis Lasagna, MD, including commencement speeches and correspondence.
  This series is not arranged.
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  - Sackler publications, 1983 -- 2014; UA171-003 (Box 16)
  - Grade reports, 2006 -- 2013; UA171-004 (Box 20)
  - Office files and history, 1979 -- 2011; UA171.004.021
    20 years from date of creation.
    - Sackler School historical summary, 1980 -- 1982; UA171.004.021.00001; 4 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
    - Medical scientists training program, 1979 -- 1982; UA171.004.021.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Outline for planning and development of Sackler School, 1981; UA171.004.021.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Progress report, 1980-03; UA171.004.021.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Leskowitz correspondence, 1982 -- 1984; UA171.004.021.00005; 2 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 8-9)
    - Lasagna commencement speeches, 1985 -- 2000; UA171.004.021.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Annual reports, 1981 -- 2000; UA171.004.021.00007; 2 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 11-12)
    - External review of Tufts Arts and Sciences and Engineering graduate programs, 2000 -- 2001; UA171.004.021.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Course listings, 1989 -- 2003; UA171.004.021.00009; 2 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 14-15)
    - Self-study report, 1992; UA171.004.021.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Accreditation, 1986 -- 1990; UA171.004.021.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - NEASC report following site visit, 1992; UA171.004.021.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Composite class photos, 1991 -- 2011; UA171.004.021.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Student handbooks, 1984 -- 2010; UA171.004.021.00014; 2 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 20-21)
    - Commencement exercises, 1988 -- 1999; UA171.004.021.00015; 2 Folder(s) (Box 21, Folder 22-23)
  - Sackler School, founding documents, 1980 -- 1990; UA171.004.022
    - Sackler School founding documents, 1980 -- 1990; UA171.004.022.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Graduate schools review reports, 1983; UA171.004.022.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Grade books, 1962-1985; Grade sheets, 1967-2013; Student files, 2006-2009, 1962 -- 2013; UA171-005 (Box 23)
  - Sackler Building photograph, 1984 -- 2008; UA171-024 (Box 24)
  - Building Diversity in Biomedical Sciences (BDBS) accepted application files, 1992 -- 2003; UA171-025 (Box 25)
  - Building Diversity in Biomedical Sciences (BDBS) accepted application files, 2004 -- 2011; UA171-026 (Box 26)